<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Delhi Yatri</string>
    <string name="copyright"> Copyright \u00a9 Delhi Yatri!</string>

    <string name="chandanichauk">Moonlight Square is the English name for the Chandni Chowk, one of the oldest yet busiest markets in Delhi. A major attraction in India is this vibrant market that provides A to Z items you would like to buy at the best rates. The Red Fort is a part of the square. The compilation of the marker was happened in the 17th century by the then Mughal emperor Shah Jahan and its design was done by his daughter Jahanara.\n\n

It was divided by canals to reflect moonlight and still, it is considered to the largest wholesale market in Delhi. There are records blowing light to its history that says its birth was happened during the founding of the capital city of Shahjahanabad with the existence of the Red Fort. Originally, the market contains 1560 shops, the square is 40 yards wide and 1520 yards long. There is a pool in the centre of the complex which makes the bazaar illuminate. The bazaar gave space to a number of silver merchants.\n\n

But later, the pool in the complex was replaced by a clock tower during the 1950s. The chowk runs through the heart of the walled city from the Lahori Gate of the Red Fort to Fatehpur Masjid. There are separate markets for sarees, suits, electronic items, accessories, ornaments, footwear, food items, shawls, sherwanis, decoration materials, lanterns, colourful dresses and what not. Chandni Chowk itself has a metro station near the market and it is the easiest way to reach the square.\n\n

Chandni Chowk entry timing:\n
The shops at Chandni Chowk would be open on all days except on Mondays from 10:00 am to 07:00 pm.\n\n

Chandni Chowk entry fee:\n
No entry fee is applicable to enter the square.\n\n

Chandni Chowk location:\n
Kaccha Bagh Area, Old Delhi, New Delhi, Delhi 110006.\n\n

Insider Tips:\n\n

    - Must visit the Parantha Wali Gali.\n

    - Visit the famous Natraj Chat and Dahi Bhalle.\n

    - Papri Chaat on the opposite side of Gurudwara, or roadside kababs near Jama Masjid defines Chandni Chowk. A visit to the place without trying such delicacies would be incomplete.</string>

    <string name="jamamasjid">The people of Delhi consider the Masjid-I Jahan Numa close to them, hence call it fondly as the Jama Masjid of Delhi. It is one of the largest mosques in India which was built by Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan between 1644 and 1656. During that time, the construction of the mosque took around 1 million rupees. Imam from Bukhara inaugurated the building after its completion. The mosque is protected by three great gates and four towers. Also, there are two 40 meter high minarets created on red sandstone and white marble standing.\n\n

The courtyard boasts its space that can accommodate more than 25000 people at a time. The three domes seen on the terrace are surrounded by the two minarets as well as the floor is comprised of 899 black borders marked for worshippers. The mosque has witnessed two attacks recently, in 2006 and in 2010. There were more than 5000 workers who contributed their sweat and blood for the construction of the masjid. The original name of the mosque meant the mosque that commanding view of the world.\n\n

Though the British wanted the mosque to be destroyed, they could not succeed in the process due to rigid opposition and protests. The largest mosque in India is a mesmerizing monument which was the last one built under Shah Jahan’s power. The masjid is located at a walkable distance from Old Delhi railway station and ISBT Kashmere Gate.\n\n

The masjid that got its life because of the architectural brilliance of Ustad Khalil is now protected by Delhi Waqf Board.\n\n

Jama Masjid entry timing:\n
Entry to the mosque is on all days from 07:00 am to 12:00 pm and from 1:30 pm to 06:30 pm.\n\n

Jama Masjid entry fee:\n
You can enter the temple free of charge but for photography, you should pay Rs.200-300 and for climbing the southern minaret, you are supposed to pay Rs.100.\n\n

Jama Masjid location:\n
Meena Bazaar, Jama Masjid, Chandni Chowk, New Delhi, Delhi 110006.\n\n

Insider Tips:\n

    - During the morning hours, crowd will not be there and it is the best time to visit the mosque.\n\n

    - You should dress modestly as it is a sacred place and women should cover their head with a shawl or similar clothes.\n\n

    - You can carry a bag to keep your shoes safe to avoid getting them stolen or be at the counter and wait for long.\n\n

    - Remember, there will be touts to harass you for unnecessary fees and avoid them.\n\n

    - There will be a separate fee to climb up the minaret that offers you a panoramic view.\n\n

    - The nearest metro station is Chawri Bazaar.\n\n

    - You should remove the shoes at the top of the stairs (pay the site minder Rs 5 upon collection).\n\n

    - Avoid fake guides insisting there's a charge to enter the mosque (admission is free).\n\n

    - For non-Muslims, the visiting timings are 07:00-12:15, 13:45-30 minutes before sunset; from 12:15 pm to 02:00 pm, it will be closed.\n

    - Tourists can take the photograph of the Mosque. A nominal fee of Rs. 200 is charged for photography and you can bring your own camera.</string>
    <string name="indiagate"> India Gate has its original name as All India War Memorial that was built in order to commemorate the 82000 soldiers of the Indian Army who lost their lives during the First World War happened from 1914 to 1921 as well as in the Third Anglo-Afghan War. The war memorial is situated at Rajpath where you can reach by getting down at Barakhamba Road Metro station in Delhi.\n\n

India Gate is located on the eastern edge of the ceremonial axis of Delhi and it was formerly called Kingsway. The names of around 13300 servicemen including some soldiers and officers from the United Kingdom are displayed on the gate. The architecture of India Gate is world famous as the triumphal arch that looks like the Arch of Constantine and also compared to the Arc de Triomphe and the Gateway of India in Mumbai.\n\n

The designer of the memorial was Sir Edwin Lutyens. After the Bangladesh Liberation War in 1971, there was a simple structure including a black marble plinth with a reversed rifle which was capped by a war helmet and bounded by four eternal flames built under the Memorial Archway. This one was the Amar Jawan Jyoti or the Flame of the Immortal Soldier.\n\n

The construction of India Gate was started in 1921 and completed in 1931. The architectural dimensions of the structure say that it is 42 meters tall and 9.1 meters wide. It was constructed using yellow and red sandstone along with granite. In 2014, the Government announced the plans to construct a National War Memorial around the canopy as well as a National War Museum at the park nearby.\n\n

India Gate Parade or the Republic Day Parade is the most ceremonious and prestigious event happen in front of India Gate every year. On January 26th, each year, India commemorates the day it became a republic with an esteemed presence of many national as well as dignified guests from other countries.\n\n

India Gate entry time:\n
Anyone can visit India Gate anytime as it is open on all days 24 hours.\n\n

India Gate Entry fee:\n
There is no entry fee to visit the structure.\n\n

India Gate location:\n
Rajpath Marg, India Gate, New Delhi, Delhi 110001.\n\n

Insider Tips:\n

    - The climate during the months from October to March will be favourable for sightseeing tours in Delhi. You can enjoy visiting India Gate with your family and friends peacefully during that time.\n\n

    - It will be fun if you bring cooked or packaged food with you, and have a picnic. You can also go for boating at the Boating Club adjacent to India Gate grounds.\n\n

    - The nearest metro station to India Gate is Central Secretariat (Yellow Line). The metro station has more than one exit gate so that you can seek the help of customer service about the closest gate to India Gate.\n\n

    - Take an auto rickshaw or the shuttle rickshaw/rickshaw service to India Gate from the metro station. Bus service can also be availed depending on your boarding point.\n\n

    - In case you are there in January, you can attend the Republic Day parade on 26th January.</string>
    <string name="indiragandhi">The former residence of one of India’s Prime Minister Indira Gandhi, set in off white colour now is Indira Gandhi Memorial Museum located on a massive area beautified with well-maintained lawns and lined by shady trees, plants, gardens, bushes, and flowers. The museum is dedicated to the memory of late Mrs. Indira Gandhi after she was assassinated within this mansion on 31st October 1984. The rooms are properly furnished and a few personal belongings of Mrs. Gandhi can be seen here through the large picture windows.\n\n

Also, the museum displays rather a beautiful collection of rare photographs covering the nationalist movement and also some important pictures of the Nehru-Gandhi families. Another important possession inside the museum is the blood-stained sari Indira Gandhi wore on the day she was assassinated. The place where her body was lying has been marked and covered with a glass frame and that is a memorial site in her honour. The museum is a beautiful kaleidoscope of historical events woven so remarkably and presented to the visitors with life beating inside them still.\n\n

It is located on Safdarjung Road and the nearest metro station to the museum is the INA Metro Station on the yellow line. The museum is a must visit to know the life of the controversial Prime Minister as she was known to many. The pictures of her childhood and the years she had grown up through are presented and preserved well inside.\n\n

Indira Gandhi Memorial Museum entry timings:\n
The museum is open all days except on Mondays from 09:00 am to 05:00 pm.\n\n

Indira Gandhi Memorial entry fee:\n
There is no entry to be paid to enter the museum.\n\n

Indira Gandhi Memorial location:\n
Safdarjung Road, New Delhi, Delhi 110011, India.</string>
    <string name="olddelhi">A tapered street in Chandni Chowk area, Paranthe Wali Gali is noted because of its sequential shops located one after the other known for selling paratha, a typical Indian unleavened thin bread. The food sold in Paranthe Wali Gali is strictly vegetarian, presented in old retrospective style without any addition of onion or garlic to the food.\n\n

This is because the owner of the particular series of a shop is a Brahmin and the neighbourhood includes the Jain population. The menu includes mix paratha, khoya parantha, rabri parantha, parat parantha. The parantha generally is served along with mint, mixed or sweet tamarind chutney, potato or paneer curry sautéed with rich sweet and spicy pumpkin.\n\n

Entry timings- The opening timings to Paranthe Wali Gali is between 9 AM to 11 PM.\n\n

Entry fee – Average cost for having food at Paranthe Wali Gali would sum up to 150 INR or 2.306 USD for two people approximately.\n\n

Location - Address of Paranthe Wali Gali is 1984-1985, Gali Paranthe Wali, Chandni Chowk, New Delhi.\n\n

Insider tips - You must try the recommended food from Paranthe Wali Gali. The recommended food is Mixed Veg Paranthe, Mirch Parantha, and Karela Parantha. </string>
    <string name="redfort">A brilliant architectural beauty is a historical fort in Delhi, Red Fort which was the main residence of the emperors of the Mughal Dynasty for more than 200 years. The Mughal families lived there until 1857. A golden feather in the crown of Delhi is the fort and it houses several museums in it. Though it was the house of the Mughal emperors, it was also the political and cultural center of the Mughal state and this was the place where a lot of significant events happened.\n\n

But what made the fort famous was the midnight speech made by Jawahar Lal Nehru before India was going to wake up to independence from British rule and afterward, it was becoming the politically significant spot in Indian history. It hosts the Independence Day celebrations each year from then onward. Red Fort history has a lot to share with the world and it came into the concept form in 1639 after the then Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan shifted his capital to the newly constructed city in Delhi and laid the foundation stone to build up the fort.\n\n

Red Fort architecture is an amusing one with a huge walled citadel that shines in red sandstone and the construction of the fort took almost one decade to complete and it came into the limelight in 1648. For the next 200 years, it was maintained as the seat of the Mughal Empire. Once the capital of the Mughal Empire, the fort lies along the famous river Yamuna. Some of the facts regarding the fort say the complex consist of Shah Jahan’s palace as well as the Salimgarh fort which came into existence in 1546 AD.\n\n

The fort is managed by the Archeological Survey of India and was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 2007.\n\n

Red Fort Light and Sound Show:\n
A spectacular show regarding the history of Red Fort and the capital Delhi is shown at the fort for one hour every evening. The show will be in Hindi and English with a half an hour gap in between the two shows.\n\n

Light and Sound show at the fort starts at 06:00 pm. To watch the Light and Sound Show, adults should pay Rs.80 and children should pay Rs.30.\n\n

Red Fort visiting timing:\n
The Fort will be closed on Mondays but will be open on all other days from 09:30 am to 04:30 pm.\n\n

Red Fort Entry Fee:\n
Entry fee for Indian citizens is Rs.10 while the same for foreigners is Rs.150.\n\n

Red Fort location:\n
Netaji Subhash Marg, Lal Qila, Chandni Chowk, New Delhi, Delhi 110006.\n\n

Insider Tips:\n

   - The nearest metro station to the Red Fort is Chawri Bazaar.\n

   - It is open from Tuesday to Sunday from 9:30 am to 4:30 pm.\n

   - Tickets for international visitors will cover museum entrance fees also.\n

   - As the parking lot is near Jama Masjid, located on the opposite side of the Red Fort, car parking is an issue. You need to take a long walk from the parking to reach the gate of the fort. Also, the traffic snarl on the connecting roads makes it difficult for the visitors to cross the roads. It is advisable to travel by taxi.\n

   - To avoid queues to get the Light and Sound show ticket, you can book it online at theashokgroup.com.\n

   - October to March is the suitable time to visit Red Fort.</string>

    <string name="qutubminar">A valuable, protected structure of India is Qutub Minar, Delhi which has been considered to be a highly important historical attraction existing currently in India. It is a part of the Qutub Complex which was declared as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. The structure is situated in the Mehrauli area of Delhi. Qutub Minar Metro Station located at a distance of about 3km will be the easiest access to reach the amazing architectural brilliance.\n\n

Qutub Minar is made of red sandstone and marble making its height up to 73 meters and gives a tower like structure to it which is consisted of five stories and its diameter is 14.3 meters at the base and it becomes 2.7 meters at the top.\n\n

Another main feature of it is the spiral staircase of 379 steps. It has been saying that the design of the tower had its origin from the Minaret of Jam located in Western Afghanistan. Qutub Minar’s founder was the legendary Qutub al-Din Aibak who was behind the existence of the Delhi Sultanate. The construction of the structure was started in 1192 and it was completed by Aibak’s successor Iltumish in 1220. But after some decades, its top storey was destructed by a lightning and later Firoz Shah Tughlaq renovated the damaged storey and constructed one more.\n\n

Around the tower, there are several historical monuments like the Qutub Complex with Quwwat ul IslaMosqueue and the Iron Pillar of Delhi. The structure of the tower has a style that resembles the architectural style prevailed in Iran but some artistic conventions found locally were incorporated such as looped bells, garlands and lotuses that are borders were carved out. One can see different inscriptions in Parso-Arabic and Nagari at different sections of the structure.\n\n

Qutub Minar entry timings:\n
The visit to the structure is restricted to the day time between sunrise and sunset on all days.\n\n

Qutub Minar entry fee:\n
For Indian citizens: Rs. 30 and for foreign nationals: Rs.500.\n
For children up to 15 years, the entry is free.\n\n

Qutub Minar location:\n
Qutub Minar Delhi is situated in Mehrauli in South West district of New Delhi, India.\n\n

Insider Tips:\n

    - Nearest metro station is Qutub Minar Metro Station.\n\n

    - It is advisable to reach as early as possible – the opening time is 7:00 AM as the complex will be less crowded.\n\n

    - Although there are shaded areas in the complex but it is always good to carry sunscreen or sunglasses especially during summer.\n\n

    - There is a Decorative Light Show every evening from 6:30 to 8:00 pm as well as the Qutub Minar Festival in October/November.</string>
    <string name="rashtrapatibhawan">The Presidential Residence, formerly known as the Viceroy’s House is the famous Rashtrapathi Bhavan in Delhi. It is the home of the President of India, officially. It is located at the western end of Rajpath. The mansion or the main building accommodates the president’s official residence, halls, guest rooms and offices. The entire 130 hectare President Estate that includes huge gardens known as the Mughal Gardens, large open spaces, a residence of office staff and bodyguards, stables etc is the major portion of it the mansion.\n\n

It is considered to be the largest residence of a head of state in the world in terms of area. The Delhi Durbar occurred in December 1911 decided to build a residence in New Delhi for the British Viceroy. In the beginning, the plan had 4000 acres of land acquired for the building after relocating Raisina and Malcha villages existed in the region. The famous British architect Edwin Landseer Lutyens was given the responsibility for the primary architecture.\n\n

The design made by Lutyens was grand and extraordinarily classical that was enhanced by different colours and details inspired by Indian architecture. Originally, the Viceroy’s House had to be built on the top of Raisina Hill along with the secretariats lower down. But it was decided to build 400 yards back and thus both the buildings had to come on top of the plateau. On this, Lutyens and Baker who was constructing the secretariat had disputes. The house consists of four floors and 340 rooms which are decorated with modified interior designs.\n\n

There were around 700 million bricks used for the construction. The design of the building was inspired by the Edwardian Baroque. It has several halls used for different functions and purposes. The main ones are the Durbar Hall and the Ashoka Hall. There is a dome in the middle that reflects both Indian and British styles.\n\n

Rashtrapathi Bhavan entry timing:\n
The mansion can be visited on all days from 09:00 am to 04:00 pm but the Mughal Garden and other gardens will be open from August to March on Friday, Saturday, and Sunday.\n\n

Rashtrapathi Bhavan entry fee:\n
There is a registration charge of Rs.50 and it can be paid online as well as it will be non-refundable and non-transferable. Visitors individually or in a group of fewer than 30 people will be charged Rs.50 per visitor and for a group of 30, it will be 1200 per visit.\n\n

Rashtrapathi Bhavan location:\n
Rashtrapati Bhawan, President's Estate, New Delhi, Delhi 110004.\n\n

Insider Tips:\n

    - You can book the entry ticket to Rashtrapathi Bhavan online via "http://rashtrapatisachivalaya.gov.in/rbtour”.\n\n

    - Cameras are not allowed inside the building.\n\n

    - You need not pay the guide.\n\n

    - The various circuits of the Bhavan are:\n
     Circuit 1: Rashtrapati Bhavan Main Building and the Central Lawn will be open on Fridays, Saturdays and Sundays.\n\n
     Circuit 2: The Rashtrapati Bhavan Museum Complex [RBMC] comprising the Clock Tower, the Stables and the Garages will be open on all days except Monday.\n\n
     Circuit 3: The Mughal Gardens and other Gardens of Rashtrapati Bhavan will be open from August to March on Fridays, Saturdays and Sundays.\n\n

    - Entry to Rashtrapati Bhavan for visit is through Gate No.2 (Rajpath); Gate No.37 (via Dalhousie Road-Hukmi Mai Marg); and Gate No.38 (via Church Road-Brassy Avenue) of Rashtrapati Bhavan.\n\n

    - Indian Citizens should carry valid photo ID Cards. In case of foreigners, they should make their request for visit along with photocopies of their passport. On the day of visit, they are required to carry their original passport for identification.</string>
    <string name="dummytextshort">Lorem Ipsum is simply dummy text of the printing and typesetting industry. </string>
</resources>
